<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on Ef&#39;s log</title>
    <link>https://fahmifj.github.io/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on Ef&#39;s log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 13:07:13 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahmifj.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Nano Blogs</title>
      <link>https://fahmifj.github.io/blog/about-nano-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 13:07:13 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahmifj.github.io/blog/about-nano-blogs/</guid>
      <description>This blog has been up for about two months (or about a year on Medium). I&amp;rsquo;m quite satisfied with what I&amp;rsquo;ve written so far, even though some of them have only 10 viewers😅.
As someone who constantly takes notes on almost everything I learn, I thought it would be fun to share these notes, particularly on IT/Cyber Security topics, on my blog, but I was wrong; it&amp;rsquo;s not as simple as I thought the first time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog has been up for about two months (or about a year on Medium). I&rsquo;m quite satisfied with what I&rsquo;ve written so far, even though some of them have only 10 viewers😅.</p>
<p>As someone who constantly takes notes on almost everything I learn, I thought it would be fun to share these notes, particularly on IT/Cyber Security topics, on my blog, but I was wrong; it&rsquo;s not as simple as I thought the first time. Converting those notes into a proper article structure has left me feeling overwhelmed, especially in the introduction section 😅.</p>
<p>And recently, I&rsquo;ve had a few people reach me about featuring my article/post in their publication. I&rsquo;m happy with that because my posts can reach a broader audience, but, at the same time, I have started to worry about my writing, especially the grammar.</p>
<p>To get over that insecurity, I had to review my post more than 2 times, check the sentence&rsquo;s structure, translate it ID-EN, and other things that would make it look just right, at least for me. I know this would improve my English, but still, it&rsquo;s not an easy task to do and it takes more time now to just write one post where I still have a lot of notes that I want to share, which keeps increasing day by day.</p>
<p><img class="img-container" src="imgs/image-20210611140231107.png" alt="image-20210611140231107"  />
</p>
<p>Not to mention that there are some untouched drafts in my Medium 😅.</p>
<p>After reflecting on my first objective of starting a blog and realizing that I&rsquo;m an amateur writer who doesn&rsquo;t aim for publication, but to share my notes and preserve my experiences, I decided to &lsquo;ignore&rsquo; publication for now and start with something called a bite-sized post/article which is short and to-the-point post (CTF write-ups are excluded 😂).</p>
<p>With that I hope I could turn my notes into a blog post quickly without worrying too much about grammar.</p>
<p>Well, it&rsquo;s not that I don&rsquo;t need a publication; I&rsquo;m totally fine increasing my audience from publication, which without a doubt motivates me to write more. But that&rsquo;s not my priority right now, and, after all, I&rsquo;m just an amateur who blogs as a hobby.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
